A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Laboratory of Electronics, Subject Files FA833
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Laboratory of Electronics, Subject Files
1949-1985
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA833
0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box.
1 box.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 421-4
Other Finding Aids
FA227 Rockefeller University records, Laboratory of Electronics, Technical Report
Biographical / Historical
After Detlev Bronk became President of the Rockefeller Institute in 1953, he decided to strengthen the already existing Electronics Laboratory by hiring John P. Hervey, a professional electrical engineer. Hervey, in turn, hired Dr. C. Yang to be his assistant. When Yang left for China in 1956, Robert L. Schoenfeld replaced him. While Hervey was in charge of long-term projects at the Institute's Jacques Loeb Laboratory in Woods Hole, Massachusetts, Schoenfeld ran the laboratory in New York, working on development and research.
Scope and Contents
Includes primarily publications (reprints and technical reports); also includes correspondence and personnel material.
Subjects include policy matters and the National Academy of Engineering.
Correspondents include Detlev W. Bronk.
Arrangement
Alphabetical.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Plant diseases; Diseases; Animals -- Diseases; Biology -- Research; Medical technology; Life sciences; Medical education; Medical sciences; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Technology; Medical research; Pathology; Medicine, Preventive; Biochemistry
- Correspondence-General, 1963-1964 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Encyclopedia Americana Article, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hervey-Neg. Cap. Probe Mass, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- National Academy of Engineering, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Original Drawings - "Computers in Medicine and Biology", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Personnel, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Policy Matters, 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Schoenfeld Reprints, 1949-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Schoenfeld Reprints, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Schoenfeld Reprints, 1970-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- U.S. National Committee for Pure and Applied Biophysics, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Publications, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Rockefeller Institute Quarterly, Winter 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Laboratory of Electronics Technical Report #1. Robert Bornmann and Michael Chen. "LIS-II Based Constant Current Stimulator", 1979 February (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Laboratory of Electronics Technical Report #2. Gordon Silverman (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Microprocessor Controlled Instruments for Data Acquisition in Behavioral Research", 1979 February (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Laboratory of Electronics Technical Report #4. Robert Bornmann and John Lehman. "LSI-II Based Average-Histogram Generator", 1980 May (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Laboratory of Electronics Technical Report #5. Robert L. Schoenfeld, Stanley Habib and Owen B. Smith. "Experience with Modula for Laboratory Applications", 1981 October (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Electronics. Printed by The Rockefeller University, 1985 or 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters of Testimony for renewal of "Microprocessor Bio-technology Resources Grant, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)